<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terraform on Austin Barnes</title><link>https://www.cinderblook.com/categories/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in Terraform on Austin Barnes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cinderblook.com/categories/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform - Azure-K8S-Deploy</title><link>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-azure-k8s-deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-azure-k8s-deploy/</guid><description>Overview Deplying a Kubernetes Cluster in Azure with the AKS service.
Build a Kubernetes cluster in Azure Have the cluster setup to automatically scale with load Have Kubeconfig file available so it can be managed, changed, altered, destroyed, etc. Ensure Kubeconfig file is secure, and is being encrypted with traffic involved in this Check out all of the configuration files on GitHub at the repository!
Steps to do this Have an Azure account; if you are a student, sign up for a student account and get some free credits along side it.</description></item><item><title>Terraform - Azure-Serv-Deploy</title><link>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-azure-serv-deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-azure-serv-deploy/</guid><description>Overview Deploy and Configure 4 Windows 2022 Datacenter Servers in Azure.
Using Terraform in conjunction with Ansible and cloudinit: Create 4 Windows Servers Configure them to be a Primary Domain Controller, Replica Domain Controller, DHCP server, and Fileshare server Automate intial setup of the 4 servers to accept Ansible configuration from a Linux VM in Azure created VIA the Terraform deployment Check out all of the configuration files on GitHub at the repository!</description></item><item><title>Terraform - vSphere-WinServ-Deployment</title><link>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-vsphere-winserv-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-vsphere-winserv-deployment/</guid><description>Overview The goal of this project is to deploy a ready-to-go windows server environment. This includes a domain controller, a replica domain controller, a DHCP server, and a fileserver. Additionally setting up users, groups, and OUs for the respective users within the domain. To complete this project, 3 steps are taken.
Use Packer to spin up a sys prepped and fully updated windows server 2022 iso for the environemnt Use Terraform to deploy 4 virtual machines into a vSphere environment Use Ansible to configure these 4 virtual machines as desired Check out all of the configuration files on GitHub at the repository!</description></item><item><title>Terraform - Proxmox-VM-Deploy</title><link>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-proxmox-vm-deploy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cinderblook.com/projects/terraform-proxmox-vm-deploy/</guid><description>Overview Using Terraform to deploy virtual machines in Proxmox. This is designed with Proxmox Virtual Environment version 7.1 in mind.
Check out all of the configuration files on GitHub at the repository!
Purpose I have a Proxmox server in my homelab, and wanted to have an easier way to spin up virtual machines on an as needed basis.
Prequisites Have a Proxmox server Have a template made on Proxmox, in my case, I used Ubuntu Server 20.</description></item></channel></rss>